JUJUTSU KAISEN
Hidden Inventory/Premature Death
1 Year Later
August 2007
Here we go.
Yeah, it's working.
Ugh, what the heck was that?
Automatic selection of targets
for your jujutsu technique?
Yup.
Though, to be precise,
I'm the target for the technique.
I've automated what I used to do manually.
Now it can discern an object's danger level
based on the strength of its cursed energy,
its mass, its velocity, and its shape.
I'd like to get it to discern poisons, too,
but that's still proving difficult.
This will allow me to keep
my Limitless technique active
almost perpetually with minimal resources.
Having it perpetually active
will fry your brain.
But I can also keep running
the reverse cursed technique
with the energy I generate on my own.
So I'm constantly giving it
a fresh brain to work with.
I'd already been working on shortening
my hand seals. That's nailed now, too.
So I can also activate multiple
instances of Blue and Red simultaneously.
The only remaining hurdles are
Domain Expansion and
teleportation over long distances.
I should be able to get
that down if we set up
some courses without any
obstacles in Jujutsu High.
Shoko, could you lend me some lab rats?
Uh...
Satoru had become the "strongest."
Suguru, have you lost weight?
You okay?
He handled all of his missions alone,
and Shoko was never sent out on
dangerous missions in the first place,
which naturally meant I was sent
on missions alone more often, too.
It's just heat fatigue.
I'll be fine.
Did you eat too much somen?
Things were busy that summer.
Episode 29
Premature Death
Likely spurred by the frequent
disasters of the past year,
cursed spirits were
springing up like maggots.
Exorcise, absorb.
Over and over.
Exorcise.
Absorb.
No one else understands
what cursed spirits taste like.
It's like swallowing a dirty rag that's
been used to clean up shit and vomit.
Who am I doing this for?
Exorcise.
Absorb.
Ever since that day,
I've been telling myself,
"What I witnessed isn't uncommon."
"I understood the ugliness of the masses,
"and still chose to be a
jujutsu sorcerer to save others."
"Don't waver."
"Fulfill your duty as a
strong jujutsu sorcerer."
Damn monkeys...
Geto-san!
Haibara...
Good work out there!
Want something to drink?
Huh? No, I'd feel bad!
But I'll take a cola!
I'm going pretty far away
for my mission tomorrow.
That so?
Bring back souvenirs.
Of course!
Do you prefer sweet stuff or salty stuff?
Satoru might eat some, too, so... sweet, I guess?
Got it!
Haibara...
Do you think you can keep going as a
jujutsu sorcerer? It's not too hard for you?
Well...
I'm not really one to think
about things too deeply,
so it feels really good to be able to
give my all to something I can actually do.
I see.
Yeah, it does.
Are you Geto-kun?
What kind of woman is your type?
Who are you?
I like girls who eat a lot!
Oh?
Haibara...
It's okay.
She's not a bad person.
I'm a great judge of character!
You say that while sitting next to me?
Yes!
He was being sarcastic, you know.
Excuse me.
Your underclassman?
He's cute. I like how frank he is.
I think he should be more
suspicious of people as a sorcerer.
So, are you not going to answer?
Please answer my question first.
Who are you?
Special-grade sorcerer Yuki Tsukumo.
That ring any bells?
You're her?
Oh, I like the sound of that! What do they say?
That you're a special-grade
who never accepts any missions,
and you're a good-for-nothing
who's been wandering around abroad.
I hate Jujutsu High.
She's pouting...
She's pouting.
I'm joking.
Though it's true that I don't get along
with Jujutsu High's policies.
What they're doing is just treating symptoms,
and I want to do something
to treat the cause.
Treat the cause?
Rather than hunt down cursed spirits,
I want to create a world
where cursed spirits aren't born.
Care for a little lesson?
What are cursed spirits to begin with?
They're creatures that take
shape when cursed energy
leaking from humans
builds up like sediment.
Excellent.
Now this means there are two ways to create
a world where cursed spirits aren't born.
One: Eliminate cursed energy from mankind.
Two: Make it possible for all of humanity
to control their cursed energy.
I thought number one had a
pretty good chance of working.
There was a model case for it, too.
A model case?
Someone you know well.
Toji Zen'in.
I've seen plenty of cases
where a Heavenly Pact reduced
a person's cursed energy to the
level of your average person,
but you could search the
whole world only to find
he was the only case in which
that cursed energy dropped to zero.
That wasn't the only intriguing
thing about him, either.
Even though Zen'in Toji
had zero cursed energy,
he was able to perceive cursed
spirits with his five senses.
By completely casting aside cursed energy,
his body drew a hard line
and actually gave him
great resistance to curses.
He truly was superhuman.
You shouldn't be ashamed of losing to him.
I wanted to try studying him,
but he turned me down.
It was a real shame to lose him.
And there aren't many people
with Heavenly Pacts,
so I'm currently favoring route number two,
making it possible for all of humanity
to control their cursed energy.
Did you know?
Cursed spirits aren't born from sorcerers.
Of course, that excludes cases
where the jujutsu sorcerer
turns themselves into a curse after death.
Compared to non-sorcerers, jujutsu sorcerers
leak extremely little cursed energy.
There's some variance based
on the sorcerer's capacity
and the amount of cursed
energy their technique expends,
but the main reason is their flow.
Jujutsu sorcerers circulate cursed
energy through their own bodies well.
To put it in rough, general terms,
if all of mankind were jujutsu sorcerers,
curses wouldn't be born.
Then you could solve it simply
by killing all non-sorcerers.
Geto-kun.
That's possible.
Huh? But...
I mean, that's probably
the easiest way to achieve it.
Just keep culling non-sorcerers and
force them to adapt into sorcerers
as a survival strategy.
You would be forcing them to
evolve using fear and danger,
the same way birds gained wings.
But unfortunately, I'm not
crazy enough to do that.
Do you hate non-sorcerers, Geto-kun?
I don't know.
I always thought jujutsu sorcery
existed to protect non-sorcerers.
But lately, the value of non-sorcerers
has been wavering in my mind.
The admirability of the weak...
The ugliness of the weak...
I find myself struggling to discern
the difference and accept those things.
There's a part of me
that despises non-sorcerers,
and a part of me that wants to reject that part.
My vision for what lies at
the end of the marathon game
of being a jujutsu sorcerer is so vague now
that I can't tell which
represents how I truly feel.
Neither one is how you truly feel.
You're not at that stage yet.
This part of you despising non-sorcerers,
and this part of you rejecting that,
are both just possibilities
that you're considering.
It's up to you to choose which part
becomes your true
feelings from here on out.
See you later.
It's a shame I didn't get to
talk to Gojo-kun, too,
but it looks like I missed him today.
I hope the three of us can all
get along as fellow special-grades.
I'll pass that along to Satoru.
Oh, right, one last thing.
You don't need to worry
about the Star Plasma Vessel.
Either there was already another
Star Plasma Vessel at the time,
or a new Star Plasma Vessel
has already been born.
Either way, Tengen is stable.
I'm sure.
Oh...
Oh, I didn't get his type.
I didn't get his type.
It was supposed to be an easy mission to
exterminate a second-grade cursed spirit!
Damn it!
Their faith in Ubusunagami...
That was a local deity.
That was a first-grade case!
You need to rest for now, Nanami.
Satoru has taken up your mission.
Can't we just leave everything
up to him alone at this point?
This marathon game of being
a jujutsu sorcerer...
If the only thing waiting at the end
is a mountain of our
comrades' corpses, then...
What is this?
What, you ask?
These two are responsible
for the latest incidents, right?
No, they're not.
These two are crazy!
They used their mysterious powers
to attack the villagers!
I've already exterminated
the cause of those incidents.
My granddaughter was nearly
killed by these two, too!
That's because she—
Shut up, you monsters!
Your parents were just as bad!
It... It's okay.
I knew we should have killed you
two when you were babies!
This part of you despising non-sorcerers,
and this part of you rejecting that..
It's up to you to choose which part...
Everyone, shall we step
outside for a moment?
...becomes your true
feelings from here on out.
What?!
Why?!
No!
...112 residents of the village were killed,
after which a fire...
(By the time Jujutsu High investigated
on September 23rd...
Investigations confirmed that all 112 were...
...residuals revealed to be the work of
Suguru Geto's curse manipulation.
Investigations confirmed that all 112 were killed by a cursed spirit,
which the residuals revealed to be the work
of Suguru Geto's curse manipulation.
...sentenced to death.
Huh?
Don't make me repeat myself.
Suguru killed everyone in the village and—
I heard you the first time.
That's why I said, "Huh?"
Suguru's old home was already
an empty husk, as well.
Though, from the bloodstains and residuals, he most likely killed his parents, too—
Like hell he did!
Satoru.
I don't understand what's going on, either.
Huh?
A high
schooler?
Need a light?
Hey.
It's the criminal.
Need something?
Just testing my luck, I guess.
I'll go ahead and ask...
Any chance the charges are false?
Nope. Unfortunately not.
I'll ask further, then. Why?
I'm going to create a world
of only jujutsu sorcerers.
I don't get it.
I'm not a child.
I'm not holding out hope
that everyone will understand.
Sulking over the idea that
no one will understand you
sounds pretty childish to me, though.
Hey, Gojo?
I found Geto.
Yeah, Shinjuku.
No way. I don't want to get killed.
Explain yourself, Suguru.
You already heard from Shoko, right?
That's all there is to it.
So you're just going to kill
everyone who's not a sorcerer?
Even your parents?!
I can't allow my parents
to be a special exception.
Besides, those people
aren't my family anymore.
That's not what I was asking!
I thought we weren't allowed to
kill when there's no point to it!
There is a point to it. Significance, too.
Even a great cause.
There's not!
You're going to kill all non-sorcerers and
create a world of only jujutsu sorcerers?!
You know that's impossible!
There's no point in chipping away bit by bit
at something you can't possibly do!
How arrogant.
Huh?
You could do it, couldn't you, Satoru?
Yet you would try to convince someone else
that it's impossible to do
something that's possible for you?
Are you the strongest
because you're Satoru Gojo?
Or does being the strongest
make you Satoru Gojo?
What are you trying to say?
If I were able to become you,
this foolish ideal would become a lot
more grounded and real, don't you think?
I've decided how I'll live my life.
Now it's just a matter of doing
the best I can to achieve that.
If you want to kill me, then kill me.
There would be a point to that.
Why didn't you pursue him?
You're actually asking me that?
Nah, it's fine.
My bad.
Sensei, I'm strong, right?
Yeah, brazenly so.
But apparently, it's not good enough
for just me to be strong.
The only ones I can save
are those who are already ready
to be saved by another.
I thought the Star Religious Group
was already dissolved.
It's a different group,
but their roots are the same.
They're claiming they just bought
the existing space as-is.
Don't like it?
No, it doesn't matter, as long as
I can gather curses and money.
Are you really going out dressed like that?
Why not? A little showmanship is important.
Geto-sama...
Watch closely.
They're all there, right?
All the branch directors,
all the representatives, and the president.
All the big donors, as well.
Test, test. Sorry for the wait, everyone.
Now, I'll keep this brief.
From this moment onward,
this organization belongs to me.
I'll be changing the name, too,
so everyone, please be sure to follow me.
Many Objected
Now, that's not good.
I know!
Sonoda-san, if you wouldn't mind,
please come to the stage.
Yes! You there!
Now, once again.
I hate monkeys.
You obey me now...
That's the true feeling I chose.
...monkeys.
You're Megumi Fushiguro-kun, right?
Who are you?
And what's with that weird face?
You look just like him, is all.
My own issue.
So listen. About your dad...
He's from this big shot jujutsu
sorcerer family called the Zen'in,
but they're such scumbags
they make even me sick,
and that's why your dad left
the family and had you.
Now, you're one of the
ones who can see things,
so you're privileged there, right?
You've noticed the power
within yourself, too, yeah?
The Zen'in clan just loves strong powers.
Most become aware of their cursed
techniques around 4-6 years old.
So it's the perfect timing to sell a kid off.
So, Megumi-kun,
you were the ultimate card that your dad
kept on hand against the Zen'in clan.
Pisses you off, doesn't it?
So, about that dad of yours. I ki—
I don't care.
I have no interest in where
he is or what he's doing.
I haven't even seen him in years,
so I don't remember what he looks like.
Though I get the general idea
from what you just said.
Tsumiki's mother hasn't come home
for a while now, either.
Ah, Megumi's home!
That means they're finished with us,
and they're off enjoying
themselves elsewhere, right?
Are you really a first grader?
Well, whatever.
If you ever want to know about
your father, you can ask me.
Hup.
I think it'll be pretty interesting to hear.
Now, on to the main point.
What do you want to do?
Do you want to go to the Zen'in clan?
What will happen to Tsumiki?
If I go there, will Tsumiki be able to
find happiness? It all depends on that.
No. A hundred percent no.
I can say that with certainty.
Okay!
Leave the rest to me, then.
I might need you to push yourself a bit, though.
So do your best.
Get stronger.
Strong enough to keep up with me.
October 19, 2018
Gojo-sensei.
So even Sensei sleeps, huh?
Of course he does.
What kind of nonsense is that?
Gojo-sensei!
Oh, he's awake.
Hey, that's one of those
expensive chairs, isn't it?
Please don't fall asleep
after summoning all of us here.
Hey, no fair! I get it next, got it?!
Hey! Hurry up!
What are you smiling about?
Don't be mean! Move it!
Nothing.
How do you write "motto" in kanji?
Wait, you use katakana? It's a foreign word?
Next time, "It's Like That."
Next Episode
It's Like That
There's so much I thought I knew, but I don't.